Luzian Rhys Seeburger

Github: github.com/RhysSeeburger Email: seeburger@mpia.de
Website: rhysseeburger.github.io/ LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/rhys-seeburger/

Summary

3rd year PhD student at the Max Planck Institute for Astronomy in Heidelberg, researching dormant black holes in close binaries. Interested in Statistics and Machine Learning, and their application to large datasets in Astronomy. Keenly engaged in Science Education and Communication and always willing to share my passion for Astrophysics with others.

## **EDUCATION**

• Max Planck Institute for Astronomy & Heidelberg University IMPRS Fellow, PhD Candidate - Astronomy

Heidelberg, Germany September 2021 - current

University of Edinburgh

Edinburgh, United Kingdom September 2016 - June 2021

Max Planck Institute for Astronomy, Heidelberg

Master of Physics - Astrophysics; First Class

Vienna, Austria

Sacre Coeur Wien

Matura; Average: 1.0

September 2008 - June 2016

# Honors and Awards

• Emerson Prize (highest grades out of all graduating Astrophysics students) - 2020/21

- Integrated Masters Medal for Astrophysics 2020/21
- Edinburgh Award (Sports Union Volunteer) 2020/21
- Edinburgh Award (Leadership in Student Opportunities) 2020/21
- Senior Honours Medal for Astrophysics 2019/20
- Edinburgh Award (Student's Association: Representing Students) 2019/20
- Edinburgh Award (Work Experience) 2019
- Certificate of Merit for pre-honours in Astrophysics, Year 2 2017/18

### EXPERIENCE

F30 - Stellar CCD photometry

Summer Research Project

"The No-U-Turn sampler in Hamiltonian Monte Carlo using JAX"

Ogden Trust Teach Physics Internship

Including lesson planning, tutoring, small-group teaching

MPhys Project

"Weak Lensing Cosmology with Deep Learning"

Impington Village College
June 2021 - July 2021

May 2021 - November 2022

University of Edinburgh September 2020 - May 2021

Heidelberg University

University of Edinburgh

July 2021 - August 2021

University of Edinburgh

May 2020 - October 2020

# Royal Society of Edinburgh Cormack Vacation Scholarship

"Linking Microbial Activity to Planetary Spectra"

- Findings presented: Higgins et al. "Nutrients, Maintenance, Energy and Growth: predicting habitability, biomass and biosignatures from limited datasets" AGU Fall Meeting 2020
- $\circ\,$  Awarded to three Astronomy students each year across Scotland
- $\circ\,$  Report awarded with "Best Report" prize by the committee for that year

Telescope Group Project

Science Education Placement

University of Edinburgh

"Determining the properties of the transiting exoplanet TrES-2b and its host star"

September 2019 - March 2020

"The effect of Specific Gestures on Learning Physics"

Stewart's Melville College

Carnegie Vacation Research Scholarship

September 2019 - December 2019 University of Edinburgh

"The effect of Priors on Cosmological Analysis"

May 2019 - August 2019

• Findings presented: Royal Observatory Edinburgh Summer Student Presentations, August 2019

o Awarded to 100 students across all disciplines each year across Scotland

### SKILLS SUMMARY

• Languages Python (Advanced), Bash, C++, Julia (Basic)

• Tools & IDEs Git, Anaconda, Docker, WSL, VSCode, Atom, Spyder

• IT - general Machine Learning (Scikit, PyTorch), High Performance Computing, Microsoft Office & OpenOffice

• Soft Skills Leadership, Scientific Writing, Public Speaking

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- El-Badry, K., Rix, H. W., Cendes, Y., Rodriguez, A. C., Conroy, C., Quataert, E., ... Seeburger, R., ... Faigler, S. (2023). A red giant orbiting a black hole. Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, 521(3), 4323-4348.. A red giant orbiting a black hole. arXiv preprint arXiv:2209.06833.
- El-Badry, K., Rix, H. W., Quataert, E., Howard, A. W., Isaacson, H., Fuller, J., ... Seeburger, R., Almada, S., & Wojno, J. (2022). A Sun-like star orbiting a black hole. arXiv preprint arXiv:2209.06833.
- El-Badry, K., **Seeburger, R.**, Jayasinghe, T., Rix, H. W., Almada, S., Conroy, C., Price-Whelan, A.M. Burdge, K. (2022). Unicorns and Giraffes in the binary zoo: stripped giants with subgiant companions. Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, 512(4), 5620-5641.
- Seeburger, R., Higgins, P., Whiteford, N., Cockell, C. (subm.) Linking Microbial Activity to Planetary Spectra: CH4 Biosignatures on an Archean-Earth-like Exoplanet
- Seeburger, L. (2022) Wolkig mit Aussicht auf Edelsteinregen. Sterne und Weltraum, 08/22
- Seeburger, L. (2022) 5000 Augen erfassen die größte Galaxienkarte der Welt. Sterne und Weltraum, 07/22
- Seeburger, R., et. al. (in prep.) Disentangling Composite Spectra

## FURTHER INTERESTS

# • Education, Outreach and Tutoring

- o MPIA Outreach Fellow 2022-current
- o "Tag der Naturwissenschaften" (Science Day) at Experimenta Heilbronn Guest Scientist 2022
- o Taught Python to Ukranian Visiting Scientist 2022
- $\circ\,$  100 Hours for Astronomy Presentation for MPIA 2021
- o Physics Outreach Team Volunteer 2021
- o Peer Support Leader, Physics Peer Mentoring Scheme 2019/20

#### • Representation and Leadership

- o IMPRS generation Representative 2021 current
- o School Convener for School of Physics and Astronomy 2020/21
- o Chair for Staff Student Liaison Committee 2020/21
- o Student Representative for Degree Year Group 2020/21

#### • Activism

- o Organised LGBT+ Lunch meetings at School of Physics and Astronomy 2020/21
- o Member of Edinburgh University Sports Union Inclusion Committee 2020/21
- o Delegate for UofE for NUS LGBT+ Conference in Edinburgh 2018
- o Participated in LGBTYS Youth Summit (Falkirk) and NTC (Durham) 2016/17

#### • Theatre

o Technical Manager and Assistant roles for multiple Student Theatre Productions 2018-2021